<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflow for Statistical Analysis</title>
    <link>https://relaxed-snyder-30b307.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Workflow for Statistical Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://relaxed-snyder-30b307.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://relaxed-snyder-30b307.netlify.app/post/2021-07-09-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relaxed-snyder-30b307.netlify.app/post/2021-07-09-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Workflow of Statistical Data Analysis Instructor: Christopher Gandrud, PhD
Email: christopher.gandrud@gmail.com
About In this workshop you will learn an end-to-end and &amp;ldquo;really reproducible&amp;rdquo; workflow for statistical data analysis. The workflow is centred on the R programming language. First you will learn the basic concepts of programming for statistical analysis and how these concepts are represented in R. Then you will learn how to structure your statistical projects from data gathering through data transformation and analysis to the presentation of results in automatically generated tables papers and slideshows in a way that is really reproducible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Basics 1</title>
      <link>https://relaxed-snyder-30b307.netlify.app/post/optional-r-basics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relaxed-snyder-30b307.netlify.app/post/optional-r-basics-1/</guid>
      <description>👋 Welcome Welcome to to the course! This is the first of 2 sets of exercises introducing you to the R programming language1 that we will use throughout the workshop.
 📝 Lesson Preview  Set up R and RStudio
 The R console
 Install packages
 Objects and assignment
 Types (character, numeric, vector, data frame, list)
 Component selection
 Workspace and history
   🏁 Getting Started with R and RStudio To complete the exercises in this workshop, you will need to access RStudio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Basics 2</title>
      <link>https://relaxed-snyder-30b307.netlify.app/post/optional-r-basics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relaxed-snyder-30b307.netlify.app/post/optional-r-basics-2/</guid>
      <description>📝 Lesson Preview  Functions
 Control Flow
 if statements
 for loops
 apply()
 Advanced: Parallel computation
    Functions If objects are the nouns of the R language, functions are the verbs. They do things to objects. Let’s use the mean function as an example. This function takes the mean of a numeric vector object. Remember our numeric_vector object from Lesson 1:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
